Business continuity refers to enabling the critical
aspects of the organization to function perhaps
at a reduced capacity during a disruption caused by any form of disturbance,
attack, infrastructure failure or natural disaster.
Most incidents are minor and can be handled easily with minimal impact.
A system requires a reboot for example.
But after a few minutes, the system is back in operation and the incident is over.
But once in a while,
a major incident will interrupt business for an unacceptable length of time
and the organization cannot just follow an incident
plan but must move toward business continuity.
Business continuity includes planning,
preparation response and recovery operations,
but it does not generally include activities to support
full restoration of all business activities and services.
It focuses on the critical products and services
that the organization provides and ensures those important areas
can continue to operate even at a reduced
level of performance until business returns to normal.
Developing a business continuity plan requires a significant organizational
commitment in terms of both personnel and financial resources
to gain this commitment.
Organizational support for business continuity planning efforts must
be provided by executive management or an executive sponsor
without the proper support,
business continuity planning efforts have little chance of success.